<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Rutland TV</title>
    <link href="https://rutland.tv/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://rutland.tv" />
    <updated>2025-07-13T23:26:51+03:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Joseph Rutland</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://rutland.tv</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Charity</title>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Rutland</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://rutland.tv/charity/"/>
        <id>https://rutland.tv/charity/</id>
        <media:content url="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/32/charity.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Film and acting"/>

        <updated>2025-05-31T16:09:00+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/32/charity.jpg" alt="Three men in a line. The one in front isgiving a thumbs up." />
                    For his new release 'Charity' Joseph wanted to capture the eerie feeling of his living quaters in Vietnam. Many of the shots involving shadows were based on his own experiences in his dark windowless room. The script was translated into Vietnamese by the talented Phan&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/32/charity.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Three men in a line. The one in front isgiving a thumbs up." /></p>
                <p>For his new release 'Charity' Joseph wanted to capture the eerie feeling of his living quaters in Vietnam. Many of the shots involving shadows were based on his own experiences in his dark windowless room. The script was translated into Vietnamese by the talented Phan Quoc Anh. </p>
<p><br>Whilst preparing for the shoot, there were a couple of oversights. Joseph left the props to the last minute so he ended up paying through the nose for the mask. </p>
<p><br>Joseph also had trouble in his search for string. He traveled to every corner of Ho Chi Minh city in search for string, stopping in and chatting to the proprietors of many craft shops around the city, but was unable to find any string.</p>
<p>Joseph, however, had a stoke of luck! He asked his ever-faithful friend Callum Caddell to hold the mask onto the actor and pretend to be an extra set of arms. </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>One More For The Road</title>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Rutland</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://rutland.tv/one-more-for-the-road/"/>
        <id>https://rutland.tv/one-more-for-the-road/</id>
        <media:content url="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/38/One-More2_1.1.1.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Film and acting"/>

        <updated>2025-05-03T22:47:00+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/38/One-More2_1.1.1.png" alt="" />
                    Joseph has recently starred in the final film (During Uni) of fellow director 'Alex Fletcher'. This film was quite wild, he was brought in last second with many mishaps occuring. A group of freinds is summoned by a magical wizard who wishes to make the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/38/One-More2_1.1.1.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>Joseph has recently starred in the final film (During Uni) of fellow director 'Alex Fletcher'. This film was quite wild, he was brought in last second with many mishaps occuring. A group of freinds is summoned by a magical wizard who wishes to make the boys drink his 'wizard seed', this was very very strange indeed.</p>
<p>The scene where the second wizard arrives was origionally supposed to have a hostage trapped in the boot of the wizard's car. Also, there were little elf hats we were initially supposed to wear but it was unfortunately decided against to the sadness of many people.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Joseph in Istanbul</title>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Rutland</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://rutland.tv/joseph-in-istanbul/"/>
        <id>https://rutland.tv/joseph-in-istanbul/</id>
        <media:content url="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/40/20250125_131711.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Right Now"/>

        <updated>2025-01-28T23:04:00+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/40/20250125_131711.jpg" alt="" />
                    Joseph is a prolific lover of all things Turkish, so it utterly delighted him to finally visit the place. He got by with the small ammount of Turkish he knew. However, the most exciting thing for him was the pre-arranged meeting with artist 'C.M.Kosemen' author&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/40/20250125_131711.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>Joseph is a prolific lover of all things Turkish, so it utterly delighted him to finally visit the place. He got by with the small ammount of Turkish he knew. </p>
<p>However, the most exciting thing for him was the pre-arranged meeting with artist 'C.M.Kosemen' author of 'All Tommorows' which Joseph had arranged. They talked for hours whilst Kosemen created art for Joseph's family and freinds. </p>
<p>This was such an amazing city, Joseph wishes he could've stayed there forever.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Bye Bye Vietnam!</title>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Rutland</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://rutland.tv/bye-bye-vietnam/"/>
        <id>https://rutland.tv/bye-bye-vietnam/</id>
        <media:content url="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/41/20250122_211131.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Right Now"/>

        <updated>2025-01-22T23:11:00+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/41/20250122_211131.jpg" alt="" />
                    Finally, after months of misery, Joseph has left Vietnam for good. However he knows that there are many things he'll miss. Grab racing, cheap and cool transport, temples everywhere, koi fish cafe's, Iguanas everywhere and the feeling of independance that living in another country gave&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/41/20250122_211131.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>Finally, after months of misery, Joseph has left Vietnam for good. However he knows that there are many things he'll miss. Grab racing, cheap and cool transport, temples everywhere, koi fish cafe's, Iguanas everywhere and the feeling of independance that living in another country gave him.</p>
<p>On his last night, he sat outside by the temple and sampled 10 mins of audio recording from by the road for future projects. He also got a sneaky tattoo before he left. </p>
<p>It was time for Joseph to return home (via Turkey) to all the things he missed: freinds, family, Iceland 3 for £3 deal, Wetherspoons 3 small plates for £13 deal, his pets and of course his camera equipment.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Joseph in Jakarta</title>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Rutland</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://rutland.tv/joseph-in-indonesia/"/>
        <id>https://rutland.tv/joseph-in-indonesia/</id>
        <media:content url="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/37/IMG-20250117-WA0008.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Right Now"/>

        <updated>2025-01-18T22:29:00+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/37/IMG-20250117-WA0008.jpg" alt="" />
                    In the last leg of my trip, Joseph went to Indonesia. Possibly the best accomodation in Asia he's ever experienced. On the second day, Joseph and Christian went to the beach where a bunch of Indonesian kids kept asking questions such as 'Do you like&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/37/IMG-20250117-WA0008.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>In the last leg of my trip, Joseph went to Indonesia. Possibly the best accomodation in Asia he's ever experienced. On the second day, Joseph and Christian went to the beach where a bunch of Indonesian kids kept asking questions such as 'Do you like Apples?' 'Do you like Cats?' and various other flavours of that question. Joseph also had the worst fish and chips of his life on that beach. </p>
<p>He and Christian then ventured (On a guided tour) to a tea plantation and an active volacano. Volcanoes stink, they are absolutely aweful on the nose. Joseph nearly bought a blow-dart from a volcano woman and he's glad he didn't because they're illegal in the UK (Who knew). Afterwards, he and Christian retired to a Volcanic spar where they got their feet nice and massaged.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, this was to be the last night before Christian headed back to Finland, so they grabbed a random Indonesian man called Ricky and went to a swinging 20's themed jazz/pizza bar and the three of them had a wonderful candlelit dinner.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Joseph In Singapore</title>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Rutland</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://rutland.tv/joseph-in-singapore/"/>
        <id>https://rutland.tv/joseph-in-singapore/</id>
        <media:content url="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/42/20250114_191917.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Right Now"/>

        <updated>2025-01-15T23:20:00+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/42/20250114_191917.jpg" alt="" />
                    English weather in a tropical climate. Joseph stayed in the 'Little India' section of the City and went on many misadventures. On his first day he tried to walk as far as he could but got trapped by rain so HAD to watch the Attack&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/42/20250114_191917.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>English weather in a tropical climate. Joseph stayed in the 'Little India' section of the City and went on many misadventures. On his first day he tried to walk as far as he could but got trapped by rain so HAD to watch the Attack on Titan movie in cinemas.</p>
<p>On another occasion he spent the whole night in an Indian bar where he danced with everybody before retiring to his hospital where the man underneath him was dying from some ailment (he survived though).</p>
<p>On the final day, Christian finally arrived and they arranged to meet by the 'Merlion Statue' Joseph was pleased that it was walkable so set off. After a while he noticed his journey was getting steeper and steeper and more and more jungle-y. About 3/4 of the way there he realised that he had accidentally entered the rainforest. When he arrived at the statue (which was at the highest point in Singapore) it turned out that Christian meant a completely different statue.</p>
<p>After the confusion was settled, Joseph and Christian headed of to an Indian Cow festival where they got special cow milk which they mixed into  a terrible chicken tikka they ordered. It was not tasty.</p>
<p>Joseph enjoyed his time in Singapore but it was far too expensive for him. Could his wallet survive this again? Probably not.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Joseph &amp; The Killing Fields</title>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Rutland</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://rutland.tv/joseph-and-the-killing-fields/"/>
        <id>https://rutland.tv/joseph-and-the-killing-fields/</id>
        <media:content url="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/43/20241116_113444.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Right Now"/>

        <updated>2024-11-16T23:25:00+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/43/20241116_113444.jpg" alt="" />
                    Joseph decided that the best use of his time in Phnom Penh was to visit the killing fields. An absolutely harrowing experince, he got to see an incredible ammount of human remains as well as the tree they used for executing babies. Joseph also met&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/43/20241116_113444.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>Joseph decided that the best use of his time in Phnom Penh was to visit the killing fields. An absolutely harrowing experince, he got to see an incredible ammount of human remains as well as the tree they used for executing babies.</p>
<p>Joseph also met a variety of genocide survivors including the one pictured. This was at the former detention centre where citizens were brutally tortured for the sadistic enjoyment of the Khmer Rouge. </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Janus</title>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Rutland</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://rutland.tv/janus/"/>
        <id>https://rutland.tv/janus/</id>
        <media:content url="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/39/b830b1a8-b331-46f0-a293-186284339f71-1.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Film and acting"/>

        <updated>2024-08-11T23:00:00+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/39/b830b1a8-b331-46f0-a293-186284339f71-1.jpg" alt="" />
                    Joseph has created a film challange using four directors who all work different parts on 4 different films. A bit confusing but fun. Joseph's mind was swimming when he got this script, his first decision was to cast Ben Hillyer as Lane, unfortunatley Ben wasn't&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/39/b830b1a8-b331-46f0-a293-186284339f71-1.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>Joseph has created a film challange using four directors who all work different parts on 4 different films. A bit confusing but fun.</p>
<p>Joseph's mind was swimming when he got this script, his first decision was to cast Ben Hillyer as Lane, unfortunatley Ben wasn't avaliable but that didn't stop him. This was also the first(ish, if you don't count Fictus Medicus) film where Joseph used body doubles. Unfortunately for Lane's apartment which was supposed to be covered in empty alcohol bottles, Joseph couldn't find any.  However, he made the quick decision that the character had auto-brewery syndrome, causing the bread that Joseph strew about to turn into alcohol in the character's stomach.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Eighth Boatman</title>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Rutland</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://rutland.tv/the-eighth-boatman/"/>
        <id>https://rutland.tv/the-eighth-boatman/</id>
        <media:content url="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/30/eighth_boatman.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Film and acting"/>

        <updated>2024-06-20T15:49:00+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/30/eighth_boatman.jpg" alt="A woman in a black cape looks on while two people inspect equipment near a camera " />
                    Joseph first came up with the idea for this script during a writing exercise. He wanted to make a film that would make people come up with their own interpretations on the ending, the. It also bothered Joseph, the amount of sappy short films where&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/30/eighth_boatman.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="A woman in a black cape looks on while two people inspect equipment near a camera " /></p>
                <p>Joseph first came up with the idea for this script during a writing exercise. He wanted to make a film that would make people come up with their own interpretations on the ending, the. It also bothered Joseph, the amount of sappy short films where two strangers bond over shared loss or trauma, which felt very cookie-cutter. This film was meant as the inverse of this trope; yes, they are both experiencing loss, however the characters strongly dislike one-another and the Boatman desperately wants this disrespectful stranger to just bugger off.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Grit</title>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Rutland</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://rutland.tv/grit/"/>
        <id>https://rutland.tv/grit/</id>
        <media:content url="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/31/grit.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Film and acting"/>

        <updated>2024-04-19T16:01:00+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/31/grit.jpg" alt="Four men in white lab coats in front of a blackboard" />
                    For this one, Joseph was inspired by various analogue horror series such as 'Gemini Home Entertainment' and 'Mystery Flesh Pit National Park'. The idea writing a horror anthology which fleshes out a world in around five minuets was an interesting challange that he through himself&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://rutland.tv/media/posts/31/grit.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Four men in white lab coats in front of a blackboard" /></p>
                <p>For this one, Joseph was inspired by various analogue horror series such as 'Gemini Home Entertainment' and 'Mystery Flesh Pit National Park'. The idea writing a horror anthology which fleshes out a world in around five minuets was an interesting challange that he through himself into with abandon. It gave him the oppertunity to work with alot of actors who he had enjoyed working with in the past. <br>This project was also a collaboration with Alex and Peter, who were amazing help throughout.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
